ZiMuZu
倾情奉献
翻译
草草
滚成一个团子
翻译
桃小兔吃冰棒
showeryhe
翻译
煮粥达人
累  小酸奶!
翻译
静妹粒
冬麟
时间轴
念念
电脑狂人
第三季
第七集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
最新最快海外影视字幕下载
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
用户名:
国家科学基金网管理员
密码:
跳蚤市场
主打商品
皮礼士糖盒
体育纪念品
简·方达锻炼带
希曼手办
活跃榜
待售商品
耻辱墙
你好啊
少年泰坦思乐冰杯
麦当劳鬼脸眼镜
麦当劳ET杯子
抱歉  我不想买东西
汉堡王伊渥克族杯子  有裂痕
《花生漫画》酒杯
你好啊
那你来这儿干嘛
接电话
麦克米伦实用网络董事会投票赶走创始人
阿帕网逐步淘汰
麻省理工
伯克利
乔
斯坦福
国家科学基金网
福布斯
免费
骗子?
欢迎来到加州
Welcome to California.
-友善之州  -嗯
- Friendly state. - Yeah.
我们结婚了
We're married.
-好了  -不不  等等
- All right. - No, no, no, no. No, wait.
我要照规矩来
I want to do this right, okay?
-那么  -不
- So-- - Oh, no!
-别逗了  -当然要
- You gotta be kidding me. - Yes, yes!
-来吧  -不要  放我下来
- Okay. - Don't. Put me down.
我是想浪漫一下  好嘛
Okay. I'm trying to be romantic, okay?
我先说清楚
Just-- just for the record,
这是我的房子  你在待业中
this is my house, you're unemployed,
而这是个荒唐性别歧视的传统
and this is an absurd, sexist tradition.
怎么了  我说你待业是开玩笑的
What? I was just kidding about that employed thing.
我知道  我觉我好像扯到哪了
I know, I know. I think I-- i think I pulled something.
咱们能像正常人那样一起跨进屋吗
Can we cross the threshold together like not crazy people?
-好啊  -好
- Okay. - Okay.
这样容易些
That was easier.
好主意
Good call...
兰顿太太
Mrs. Rendon.
你太客气了  豪伊先生
You're welcome, Mr. Howe.
-是我  -乔  能够登入了
- It's me. - Hey, Joe, I got the login set up.
进去后是空白目录
It just leads to a blank directory,
但我们的网络正式启动了
but our network is officially live.
莱恩  我出局了
Ryan, I'm out.
慢着  出局  出什么局
Wait, out? Out of what?
麦克米伦实用网络
MacMillan Utility.
所以国家科学基金网也暂停了
which means NSFNET is paused.
这怎么可能呢
How-- how-- how is that even possible? It's--
我以后再解释
I'll explain later.
我要你明天照常去  装作什么事都没有
What I need is for you to go in tomorrow like nothing happened
因为你会被开除
because you're gonna be fired.
你知道得越少越好
The less you know, the better,
有人问起就说我俩没谈过
and if anyone asks, we never talked.
雷先生  咱们聊聊
Ah, Mr. Ray. Let's chat.
布鲁斯  我是戈登
Hey, Bruce. It's Gordon.
这是什么  盗版的《壮志凌云》吗
What is this? Bootleg "Top Gun"?
还要好  看就是了
Better. Just watch.
我想听你的反应
I want to hear you watch it.
麦克米伦实用网络  创始执行总裁
...founding CEO, MacMillan...
老天
Oh, jeez.
我在场时感觉就够糟了
These things are bad enough when I'm there.
要我看什么
What am I watchin' this for?
我不剧透
I don't wanna spoil it.
-看吧  -不  从没有过
- Watch. - No. Never.
-什么  -关掉
- What? - Turn it off.
别
Don't.
我  乔·麦克米伦
I, Joe MacMillan,
偷了戈登·克拉克的杀毒软件的代码
stole the code to the security software from Gordon Clark.
这家公司的根基是他的创造
Everything this company is built on is his.
见鬼了
Holyhit.
我就想听这个
That's what I wanted to hear.
我找合伙人谈过
I talked to the partners,
我们认为起码价值两千五百万
and we think this is worth at least 25 mil.
听见了吗  戈登
You hear me? Gordon?
听见了  嗯
Y-yeah. Yeah.
戈登  要迟到了
Gordon, we're gonna be late.
还好吧
Is everything okay?
嗯  一切都很好
Yeah, everything's great.
我在考虑加个
I was thinking of adding
婚戒个性化图标
a wedding ring customization.
听说你的头像可能需要
Heard your avatar could maybe use one.
我以为戈登会更早告诉你
Well, that took Gordon longer than I thought.
我可以说我为你感到高兴吗
Is it okay for me to say I'm happy for you?
可以
You can say that.
这太傻了
This is silly.
我们应该庆祝  汤姆什么时候过来
We should celebrate. When does Tom get here?
他今天早上就到了
he got here this morning.
那么  你们晚上有什么安排
Well, then... what are you doin' tonight?
有多严重
So, how bad is it?
"麦克米伦先生从一开始就知道
"Mr. MacMillan knew from the start
城堡软件绝不会一直免费
the Citadel software would never remain free.
他想收获正面公关
He wanted to reap the PR benefits
之后再去考虑谎言的后果"
and worry about the fallout from the lie later."
-天啊  -这是第一枪
- Jesus. - It's the first shot
这场仗会很难看
in what's gonna be a very ugly war.
我必须还击
I just have to return volley.
你去的时候肯怎么说的
What happened with Ken when you went in?
我想知道全部细节
I want the blow-by-blow.
我就按你说的做
I did what you told me...
也就是什么都没说
which was to say nothing,
这很容易  因为我什么都不知道
which was easy because I know nothing.
很好  既然你已经离开那儿了  我们可以
Good. Now that you're out of there, we can--
但是肯没有炒了我
But Ken didn't fire me.
什么  为什么
What? Why not?
他给你开了什么条件
What did he offer you?
他没给我开任何条件
He didn't offer me anything.
暂时没有
Not yet.
在这结束之前我们
It's probably best if we don't talk
最好别交谈也别见面
or see each other until this is over.
好吧
Okay.
莱恩  你就是这件事里的薄弱点
Look, Ryan, you're the weak link in all this.
他知道搞定我的唯一途径就是通过你
He knows the only way to get to me is through you.
还有十分钟我就要去打保龄球了
So, I'm 10 minutes away from going bowling--
我甚至都不喜欢保龄球
and I don't even like bowling--
但是  不管怎样  有人敲门了
but, anyway, there's a knock at the door.
我就开门了
And I-- I open it.
我以为是那个奇怪的邻居
I'm thinking it's that weird neighbor
问他的缅甸蟒是不是又跑到我院子里来了
asking if his Burmese python is loose in my yard again.
但不是  是卡梅伦
But, no, it's Cameron,
她脸上带着那种表情
and she has this look on her face.
我永远也忘不了
I'll never forget it.
然后呢
What happened next?
好吧  你们在婚礼之前就先度蜜月了
Okay, so you had the honeymoon before the wedding.
你是怎么求婚的呢
And, uh, how did you propose?
-严格说  我没有  -对  是我求婚
- Technically, I didn't. - Yeah, I proposed to him.
不是
Mmm, no.
严格说  你也没有
Technically, you didn't either.
-我求了  -没有
- Yes, I did. - No.
好吧  在某一时刻  卡梅说...
Yeah, at some point, Cam said...
我真希望能一直这样下去
"I wish it could be like this forever."
然后我说  可以的
And I said, "Uh, it could be."
她说  但你不会搬去加州的
And she said, "But you won't move to California."
然后  就这样
And, um, yeah.
然后他说
And then he said,
我不会为女友搬去加州
"I won't move to California for a girlfriend,
但我会为妻子这么做
but I would move there for my wife."
第二天我们就找了个治安法官
And the next day we found a Justice of the Peace.
天哪  戈登  是不是很浪漫
Oh, my God. Gordon, isn't that romantic?
什么
What?
汤姆和卡梅伦的故事
Tom and Cameron's story.
对  恭喜
Right. Um, congratulations.
-好  -谢谢  干杯
- Okay. - Thanks. Cheers.
那你要来穆特尼工作吗
So, um, you gonna come work at Mutiny?
这倒不会
Uh, actually, no.
我们觉得上次我们俩吹了就因为这个
We decided that's what killed things last time, so--
就是  工作和感情搅在一起
you know, mixing a relationship with work.
真的吗
Really?
当然  许多夫妻都是这样的
And by that, I mean that lots of couples do that,
这样很好  只是真不适合我们
and it's great. It's just-- it's just really not for us.
但我周三会过来一趟
But I'm gonna swing by on Wednesday
和大家打个招呼  我迫不及待想看到
to say hi to the guys. I cannot wait to see
他们听到这消息时的表情
the looks on their faces when they hear.
他们会大吃一惊的
They're gonna be shocked.
博斯可是一点风声都没透
You know, Bos has really kept this under his hat.
博斯
Bos.
我知道我昨晚就该过来的
Look, I know full well I should've come in last night.
你说  我听着
I'm listening.
你听说过点金术吗
Have you heard of the Midas Touch?
我正好与之相反
Well, I got the... opposite of that.
我和我前妻  儿子都不睦
I'm on the outs with my ex-wife and my son--
其实几乎和在德州打过交道的所有人都不和
hell, practically everybody I did business with back in Texas.
还有个重磅消息
And to top it all off,
我蹲过14个月监狱
I did 14 months in a federal prison.
我觉得在我跨过这道门槛前
I thought you should know that...
你该知道这些事
before I cross this threshold.
是拉图纳监狱吧
La Tuna, right?
在埃尔帕索外  中级监狱
Outside El Paso, medium security?
你真觉得我会和一个公司做生意
You really think I'd go into business with a company
却不对其关键人物做背景调查吗
and not do background checks on all of its key players?
你认为我是个关键人物吗
So, you think of me as a "key player"?
你就赶紧把花给我
Just give me the damn flowers
别在那儿没事找事了
and stop making problems where there aren't any.
我只是  我想
Look, I just-- I wanted to--
唐娜  听着
Donna, look,
我们不是只对你保密的  好吧
we weren't keeping it just from you, okay?
汤姆的妈妈上周五才知道
Tom's mom only found out last Friday.
不是  我懂的
No, I get it.
有个没人知道的秘密
It must have been fun
一定很有意思
having a secret nobody knew about.
是有那么一点
Yeah, a little.
但如果你能提前通知我你要搬出去就好了
Would have been nice to get a heads up you were moving out, though.
-孩子们很想你  -这是我不好
- The girls really miss you. - Yeah, I regret that.
听着  我只是
Look, it's just, I...
最近不是很能信任你
haven't had the easiest time trusting you lately.
我明白
No, I know.
我觉得可能是因为
I think that's probably
我骗了你
because I lied to you.
我讨厌这样
I hate it.
那感觉很不舒服  很糟糕
It's been uncomfortable and awful,
我真的很讨厌这样
and I just-- I hate it.
是啊
Yeah.
我也想再次信任你
I wanna trust you again.
真的  我希望我们之间的一切
I do. I-- I-- I want things to go back
能回到从前
the way they used to be between us.
我想念那个时候
I miss it.
我也是
I miss it, too.
那么  我们该怎么办
So, where does that leave us?
我们能重新开始吗
Can we just start over?
好
Yeah.
好  我们重新开始
Yeah, let's just... have a fresh start.
-重新开始  -没错
- A fresh start. - Yeah.
所以本着彻底坦诚的精神
So, in the spirit of complete honesty,
我也考虑了很久
I've been giving it a lot of thought,
我真的认为我们该上市
and I really think we should go public.
好  我并不完全反对
Okay. Well, I'm not completely opposed to it.
-你不反对吗  -不
- You're not? - No.
这里有上市的热潮嘛
I mean, we're in the land of the IPO.
如果我不接受的话
If I wasn't open to it,
我就应该留在德州
I would've just stayed in Texas.
想象一下能拥有
Imagine having the resources
让公司按我们意愿发展的资源
to take the company wherever we wanna go.
是啊  我的构想相当庞大
Yeah, I have a pretty big imagination.
我就指望你呢
I'm counting on it.
唐娜  你来了
Donna, you're here.
昨晚过后
So, after last night,
我一直在考虑
I haven't been able to stop thinking
在公开募股之前
about all the things we can do
该如何改善穆特尼
to upgrade Mutiny before the IPO.
我写了一些想法
I wrote down some ideas,
我认为我们应该马上执行
and I think we should get started right away.
-很多啊  -是  我知道
- There's a lot here. - Yeah, I know, I know.
我一开始
It's like once I started,
就刹不住了
the floodgates opened.
显然  你对此投入了很多精力和想法
Well, you've obviously put a lot of thought and effort into this.
确实
I did.
这不仅回归了穆特尼和跳蚤市场的本源
It totally reconfigures Mutiny and SwapMeet
还完全重塑了它们
while returning them to their roots,
取其精华  去其糟粕
excising everything that's bad and keeping what's good.
这能让我们不再受限于康懋达电脑
And, it takes us beyond the Commodore
可以在其他系统上运行
onto other platforms
这我们必须实现
which we have to do.
这是我在凌晨五点左右想到的
That became obvious around 5:00 a.m.
其他系统  对
Other platforms, right.
你认为这得花多长时间
How long do you see that taking?
一年  也许是两年
A year. Maybe two.
但目标是把它做好  对吗
But the goal is to do it right. Right?
我肯定你在这里列出来的一切都很棒
I'm sure everything that you've outlined here is great.
真的
I am.
但我们等不了两年
But we can't afford to wait two years.
我们当然等得了
Sure we can.
首次公开募股的时间表是三个月
The timeframe for the IPO is three months.
三个月吗
Three months?
没人说过是三个月
No one ever said anything about three months.
为什么突然变成三个月了
Why is that suddenly the magic number?
因为我们目前手上有个收购案
Because we have an acquisition offer in hand.
现在有人在关注我们
People are paying attention to us right now.
但我们的产品现在不行
But what we have right now is broken.
就我们现在的状态
What we have right now,
计算机服务认为值两千万美元
CompuServe thinks is worth $20 million.
对  但如果我们做出我们能做的改善
Yes, but if we make the improvements the way I know we can,
我们将值一亿美元
we'll be worth $100 million.
我以为我们已经达成一致了
I thought we were in agreement on this.
我们还是能达成一致的
We still can be.
我真的不想这么做
Okay, look, I really hate to play this card,
但作为公司负责人  我要说
but as head of the company, I'm saying
我们必须暂缓上市的事
that we'll need to put the brakes on any IPO
直到我们把自己调理好
until we get our house in order.
好吧  不如这样
Okay, how about this?
我会仔细地看看这个
I will read this more closely
更好地理解你是怎么想的
to get a better understanding of what you have in mind--
太好了  好
Great. Okay.
如果你有什么不明白的地方  就来问我
And if there's anything you don't understand, just ask me.
我保证  这么做才是对的
I promise, this is the way to go.
我刚刚挂了《福布斯》的电话
I just got off the phone with "Forbes"
他们似乎是来者不善
and it doesn't sound like a generous piece.
他们问我西方集团的事
They're asking me questions about WestGroup,
问我卡迪夫的事  还有IBM的事
questions about Cardiff, questions about IBM.
他们显然是有观点了
Listen, they've clearly got an angle
而且不是向着我的观点
and it is not one that is favorable to me.
我再打给你
I'm calling you back.
看来你和律师谈过了
I guess you talked to your lawyers.
这里...
This is...
和我想象的不一样
not what I expected.
我真喜欢那个沙发
I sure do love that couch.
你请设计师了吧
I take it you used a designer?
我和唐娜也有个这样的花瓶
And, hey, me and Donna have this same vase.
-在一号码头买的吧  -那不是花瓶
- Pier 1, right? - It's not a vase.
是我委托东京艺术家阪庭伽椰子做的
I commissioned that from Kayako Sakaniwa, a Tokyo artist.
她给它取名为"风和日丽"
She calls it "Serenity."
戈登  我想除了装修
Gordon, I imagine you have some questions...
-你还有其他问题要问吧  -并没有
- beyond the decor. - Not really.
你显然是想被解雇
You obviously wanted to get fired.
这招我以前见识过
I've seen that move fore.
没这么简单
It's, it's more complicated than that.
是吗
Yeah?
真让我吃惊
Shocker.
天呐  这景色真是绝了
Man, this is one kick-ass view.
从这儿能看见大桥
You can see the bridge from here.
我敢说这房子的钱你全都赚回来了
I'll bet you get back every dollar you put into this place.
该死  我都想从你手里买下来
Hell, I might even buy it from you--
家具  风和日丽花瓶
the furniture, the Serenity vase--
所有的一切
the whole kit and caboodle.
我从没想过让你白干
I never wanted you not to profit.
"我  乔·麦克米伦
"I, Joe MacMillan,
从克拉克电脑公司的戈登·克拉克
stole the code to our security softwa
手中偷了杀毒软件的代码
from Gordon Clark of Clark Computers.
我挣来的一切都是他的"
Everything I've earned is his."
这是你说过的最诚实的话
It's the most truthful thing you've ever said.
老实说  我被打动了
Honestly, I was moved.
没想到你是个刻薄的胜利者
I never figured you for a sore winner.
我也没想到  但是知道
Me, either, but it's nice to know
我们还能让自己意外也挺好的
we can still surprise ourselves.
我们不如废话少说
So, what do you say we cut through the bullshit
你告诉我你究竟打的什么主意
and you just tell me what your angle is in all this?
事实上
The truth is--
这是真话
and this is the truth--
我遇到了一件我深信是...
I have come across something that I am convinced is--
我真心相信的东西
well, it's something that I really believe in,
是什么我就不说了
and we'll leave it at that.
但我无法让董事会也认同它的价值
But I couldn't convince my board of its value,
所以我无视他们  放手去干了
so I ignored them, I moved forward,
就这样  我失去了我的公司
and just like that, I lost my company.
我已无计可施  然后我想到
I was out of moves, and then it occurred to me,
如果那不是我的公司呢
what if it wasn't my company?
这么说  你坑了你邪恶的公司老大
So, you screw over your evil corporate overlord
把你的股份甩给了我
by parachuting your stake out to me.
好吧  这我算明白了
Okay, I get that... sort of.
你要怎么获得最终胜利
How do you come out on top in this scenario?
我不会
I don't.
我拥有的一切都属于你了
Everything I had is yours.
如果你觉得我应得一份的话
If you feel like I deserve a percentage,
那也完全取决于你
well, that is entirely up to you.
这么说  你的打算就是让我给你钱吗
So, your plan was for me to just give you the money?
在你从我这儿偷了一切后
After you stole everything from me?
程序是你写的  我同意
You wrote the code, agreed,
但是我两次邀你入伙
but I offered you partnership twice,
你也拒绝我两次
and you turned me down twice.
我必须相信你没那么目光短浅
I have to think that you're not so myopic
以至于不能承认我把它变成了如今的样子
that you can't see that I might be entitled to a little return
也应得到一点回报
for turning it into what I've turned it into.
这件作品很有意思
This is an interesting piece.
这是谁的杰作
And whose work is this?
我的
Mine.
戈登  跟你说清楚
Gordon, to be clear,
你不需要给我任何东西
you don't have to give me anything.
谢谢你澄清了
Thanks for making that clear.
但是公司是我一手建立的
But I built an entire company
而我刚把一切都交给你了
and I've just handed you everything.
现在我只想要点中间人报酬
All I am asking for is basically a finder's fee.
乔  我真的很喜欢这个
Joe, I really do like this piece.
它叫什么名字
What do you call it?
是幅抽象画
It's an abstract.
是吗
Yeah?
但依我看
'Cause it seems to me like
像是那种
one of those paintings that
你越看
the more you look at it,
越能看清楚的画
the more it seems to come into focus.
戈登  我知道  我寄于了你很大信念
Gordon, I know this is a leap of faith on my part,
但信念  正是我的追求
but faith is somethin' I'm workin' on.
信念是一个...
Faith is a--
信念是一个很可贵的东西
faith is a valuable thing.
只是我不想把它寄托在你身上
I'd just look for somewhere else to place it.
谢谢你的公司  乔
Thanks for the company, Joe.
唐娜
Donna.
出什么事了吗
Is everything okay?
卡梅隆简直疯了
Cameron's gone off the deep end
我不知道该怎么办
and I don't know what to do.
她今天带来了这份穆特尼声明
She came in today with this Mutiny manifesto
想阻止上市
that will kill the IPO.
而且她决心已定
And she's committed to it.
她就差把这个钉在我脑门上了
She did everything but nail it to my forehead.
也许我今晚该好好研究下这个
Maybe I should take the night to read this over.
还等什么  现在就看吧  我可以等
Why wait? Why not read it now? I can wait.
因为我觉得她是不想你
Because I think she's tryin' to stop you
发现我在这儿
from figurin' out I'm here.
博斯  我...
Bos! I--
我们是最近发展起来的
It's a relatively recent development.
但别担心卡梅隆会知道
But if you're worried about Cameron finding out,
我已经一个多月没和她讲话了
I haven't talked to her in over a month.
你想说什么就说什么吧
So, say what you came to say.
-计划很多啊  -是啊
- This is a lot. - Yeah.
实施起来要多长时间
How long to implement?
一年  也许两年
A year. Maybe two.
这也等太久了
That's a long time to wait.
她为什么反对上市
Why is she against the IPO?
她并不  这就是让人抓狂的地方
She's not, and that's what makes it so frustrating,
但卡梅伦就这样
but it's what happens with Cameron--
博斯  你也知道
and, Bos, you can back me up--
她总是想做什么做什么
she gets in her own way.
这事没那么简单
It's a little more complicated than that,
但这也算没说错
but I suppose that's part of it.
那你有什么打算
So, what do you want to do?
我不知道
I don't know.
卡梅伦弄得像自己是大股东  但她不是
Cameron acts like she's majority shareholder, but she's not.
她比其他人的票数都高
She's got more votes than anyone,
但不比所有人高
but not more votes than everyone.
我还是希望你们求同存异
I'd prefer you to find common ground.
真的不行吗
Are you sure you can't?
你今早刚告诉我
Just this morning you were telling me
你很高兴地庆祝了她的新婚呢
what a wonderful time you had celebrating her marriage,
很开心能开启新的篇章
how you were excited to start a new chapter.
没错  然后她就把这玩意丢给我了
Right, and then she comes in and dumps this on me.
慢着
Back up a beat.
卡梅伦结婚了
Cameron got married?
博斯  我以为你知道
Bos, I assumed you knew.
-抱歉  -不用
- I'm sorry. - Don't be.
这事也不该你来说
Wasn't your news to tell.
你把这里布置得不错
Love what you've done with the place.
跟黛安喝酒了吗
Drinks with Diane?
没喝
Diane, no drinks.
卡梅伦对上市的事改主意了
It's Cameron. She changed her mind about the IPO.
怎么  她不想做吗
What? She wants to kill it?
这不是她的初衷
That is not her intent,
但如果按她的来  结果便会如此
but if she has her way, it will be the result.
很遗憾
Well, sorry to hear that.
一切还没定  但如果想上市
Nothing's settled yet, but moving forward
就得让所有股东否决她
means getting all the equity owners to overrule her.
我们有35%  还有黛安和博斯
We've got 35%, and then there's Diane and Bos
道格和克雷格
and Doug and Craig.
卡梅伦对这事毫不知情吗
And Cameron has no idea this is happening?
一切还没开始  还在计划阶段
Nothing is happening. It's all talk at the moment,
但我得考虑所有办法
but I have to explore every option.
我们并不占公司35%的股权
We don't own 35% of the company.
-我们有  -不  你有25%
- Yeah, sure we do. - No, you own 25%
克拉克电脑买了主机  占有10%
and Clark Computers owns 10% for buying the mainframe.
克拉克电脑  也就是我
And Clark Computers, I.E., me,
不想瞒着卡梅伦
doesn't like the idea of blindsiding Cameron
逼她接受上市
and shoving this IPO down her throat.
这...
That's-- that is--
完全不是我的意思
just a gross mischaracterization. I--
唐娜  如果你这么做
Donna, if you pull this move,
我保证她会觉得你在向她宣战
I guarantee you she'll see it as an act of war.
这是个无法挽回的过界之举
and you will cross a line that you cannot uncross.
别骗自己了
So, don't kid yourself.
今天太累了  我睡了
It's been a long day. I'm going to bed.
你见过麦克米伦先生和戈登·克拉克说话吗
Did you ever witness Mr. MacMillan talking to Gordon Clark?
没有
Nope.
麦克米伦先生曾经
Did Mr. MacMillan ever
向戈登·克拉克吐露过他的计划吗
confide any plans he had with Gordon Clark?
没有
No.
你不觉得奇怪吗
Don't you find it odd,
我们取消国家科学基金网交易
the day we eighty-sixed NSFNET
炒了乔的那天
and we shit-canned Joe
他就长了良心  说戈登发明了
he finds religion and says Gordon invented
这个公司的基石软件
the software this company's built on,
给了他的前合伙人
giving his ex-partner,
在告他的人  一切
the one suing him, everything?
也许你不知道
Or maybe you didn't know.
也许乔没告诉过你这些事
Maybe Joe didn't tell you that part.
我一直以为你也参与了
And I always assumed that you were involved.
他们没把你踢出局吧
They didn't cut you out of the deal, did they?
不用回答
No need to answer.
对不起  孩子  这事很大
Look, I'm sorry, kid. It's bigger than you.
而你只是乔牺牲掉的一个棋子
You're just a pawn that Joe sacrificed in the end game,
所以你对我们没用了
which means that you're useless to us.
也许你对他也没有用了
You're probably useless to him, too.
那么...
So...
就这样吧
that's it.
你该走了
It's time for you to go.
-我被炒了  -是的
- So, I'm fired? - Yes.
好
Good.
克拉克先生  他们在等你了
Mr. Clark? They're ready for you.
戈登  你来干什么
Gordon, what are you doing here?
莱恩  你是对的
Ryan. You were right.
你和乔合作的那个东西
That thing that you and Joe were working on?
前途无量
It's gonna be huge.
克拉克先生  不管麦克米伦先生
So, Mr. Clark, regardless of what Mr. MacMillan
自以为做到了什么
thinks he got away with,
我们都打算对其供述的真实性提出异议
we plan to fully challenge the veracity of his confession.
我觉得我们不用律师就能速战速决
Listen, I think we can speed things up without the lawyers.
我的律师就没来
I mean, I don't have mine.
不如你也叫他走吧
What do we say you lose yours?
你不是真想让我相信
You're not really gonna try to convince me
你和乔没有串通好吧
that you and Joe didn't talk about this, right?
我没打算让你信什么
I'm not gonna try and convince you of anything.
我想和你做交易
I'm here to offer you a deal
让你不需要再想那个问题
that will make that question irrelevant.
我的律师说我最少能拿到两千五百万
Now, my lawyers say I'm looking at a floor of 25 million.
-你的律师在做梦  -我只要10%
- Your lawyers are dreaming. - I'm willing to take 10% of that,
还要乔买下的装置
along with the equipment that Joe bought
和他与国家科学基金网达成的协议
and the deals that he made for NSFNET.
就算我想接受交易
Even if I wanted to make that deal,
我不能把政府合同就这么给你
I can't just hand you a government contract.
我可以把基础设施卖给你
I mean, I could trade you the infrastructure,
但你得去投标
but you would have to chase that bid.
不  我觉得为了两千万
No, I think for 20 million,
你可以打电话给地区主管
you can make a call to the sector chief
办妥这件事
and make that happen.
或者我可以起诉你  保住一切
Or I could just sue you and keep it all.
你可以  但你会输
Yeah, you could, but you'll lose,
我觉得你很清楚
and I think you know that.
按我的方式来  你能用你根本不在乎的东西
We do it my way, I'm giving you everything that you want
来换取所有你想要的东西
in exchange for nothing you care about.
我有一件事放不下
One thing sticks in my craw.
如果我们达成协议
We make this deal,
你转头就把乔想要的东西全给他了
you turn around and give Joe everything he wants
那混蛋又赢了
and that son of a bitch wins again.
你为什么觉得
And what makes you think
这里只有你
you're the only one in this room
想对付乔·麦克米伦
that wants to stick it to Joe MacMillan?
好了  赶紧把这事搞定
Okay, let's get this over with.
如果阿基利用这个理由
Remember to detach Arki from me
抱我超过正常时间
when he uses this as an excuse
你要记得把他赶走
to hug me past a socially acceptable amount of time.
我记得了
I got it, all right?
我们去吓吓他们吧  豪伊兰顿太太
Let's go fry some coders' circuits, Mrs. Howe-Rendon.
-不好  -兰顿豪伊呢
- No. - Rendon-Howe?
-我们再想吧  -好
- We'll figure it out. - Okay.
-汤姆  -兰顿
- Tom? - Rendon!
-老兄  -你怎么来了
- Dude! - What are you doin' here?
浪子回归了
The prodigal son returns.
汤姆弹
Tom the Bomb!
可算来了个好程序员
Finally, a real coding lead.
你来多久  兰顿
How long you here for, Rendon?
算是定居了
Kind of indefinitely.
-不会吧  -等等  什么
- No. - Wait a minute. What?
-是啊  我们结婚了  -什么时候的事
- Yeah, we got married! - When did this happen?
几周前在德州
A couple weeks ago in Texas.
-你不是怀孕了吧  -你看我像吗
- You're n pregnant, are you? - Do I look pregnant?
怎么没请我
Why wasn't I invited?
-过来  -天呐
- Come here, you. - Oh, God.
过来吧
Come on.
-真替你开心  -行了
- So happy for you. - Okay, all right.
-谢谢  -你真是幸运
- Thank you. - You're a very lucky man.
庆祝穆特尼首个正式婚姻
Here's to Mutiny's first official marriage!
愿你们白头到老
May it a be long and happy one.
好了  谁想来点
Okay, who wants some of that?
看上去不错啊
This looks great.
博迪  你能不能别对瓶吹了
Bodie, would you stop drinking out of the bottle, dude?
别直接对口了  拜托
Just stop drinking out of the bottle. Come on, man.
-我肯定能喝完  -你还得留肚子吃蛋糕
- I bet I can finish it. - You have to leave room for cake.
-不  -看啊
- No-- - Look it.
干什么
What, dude?
CQ  CQ
CQ! CQ!
恭喜
Congratulations.
来点蛋糕吧
Have some cake.
超市买的  这种最好了
It's supermarket bought, but that's the best kind.
化学精华
Chemical goodness.
我得跟你谈谈
I need to talk to you.
好
Okay.
别在这儿
Not here.
好
Yeah.
唐娜还是想上市
Donna wants to move forward with the IPO...
不管你同不同意
with or without you.
好吧  真是的
Okay. Tough titties.
我不想  这是我的公司
I don't want to, and it's my company.
你是多数股东
You're the plurality shareholder.
你的股份最多
You own the most.
但如果她能让
But if she gets everyone else
公司其他股东都站在她这边
with a stake in this company to side with her,
她就能否决你的决定
she can overrule you.
好吧
Okay.
道格和克雷格显然
Doug and Craig will obviously
会抓住坑我的机会
jump at the chance to screw me.
但就算她说服了黛安
But even if she manages to convince Diane,
那还有你和博斯呢  没戏的
that's still leaves you and Bos. Game over.
还有博斯
It leaves Bos.
我必须支持她
My vote's gotta be with her...
就算我反对
even if I'm against it.
对不起
I'm sorry.
她还在上面给我开派对
She's out there throwing me a party.
你要帮那个撒谎的两面派...
and you're gonna side with that lying, two-faced, bi--
小心  她还是我妻子
Careful, okay? That's my wife.
你真幸运
Lucky you.
卡梅
Cam.
-是啊  -卡梅伦
- Yeah, there's just-- - Cameron!
恭喜  我很替你们开心
Congratulations. I'm so happy for the two of you.
谢谢  能说句话吗
Yeah, thanks. Can I borrow you?
喂
Hello?
我得问你句话
I have to ask you something,
我需要你说实话
and I need you to be completely honest with me,
因为我不知道该信什么了
because I don't know what to believe anymore.
别撒谎  好吗
So, don't lie to me, okay?
你想问什么
What do you want to ask me?
你是跟戈登一起策划好的吗
Did you plan this whole thing with Gordon?
你要执行国家科学基金网的计划而不带我吗
Are you moving forward with NSFNET and cutting me out?
当然不会
No, of course not.
你为什么会这么想
Where did you get an idea like this?
我需要你帮忙
I need something from you,
我知道我们从德州回来之后
and I know things have been super awkward between us
我们之间就很尴尬
since we got back from Texas.
我该说点什么的  但我没有
I should have said something, but I didn't.
你也没
I mean, you didn't either,
但那现在不是重点
but that's not the point right now.
重点是  我知道我们现在有别的矛盾
The point is, I know it's not cool to ask for something
不该来求你帮忙
when there's this other thing between us,
但我现在真的需要你帮忙
but I really, really need your help right now.
你打算什么时候告诉我的
When were you gonna tell me?
博斯  我也才知道
Bos, I just found out myself.
我并不知道唐娜打算绕过我
I didn't know Donna was gonna try an end run around me.
你结婚的事
About your marriage.
卡梅  我知道你不把我当做父亲
Look, Cam, I know you don't think of me as a father.
你说得很清楚了  这没关系
You made that clear. That's okay.
你想怎么想就怎么想
You're gonna feel the way you wanna feel.
但我还是会把你当女儿
But it won't stop me thinkin' of you as a daughter.
告诉我怎么办
So, tell me what to do.
首先  别把你跟唐娜的矛盾扩大化
First off, don't make this thing with Donna any bigger than it is.
你俩就是意见不一致而已
You two have a difference of opinion, that's all.
我之所以会来这儿  就是因为你
The only reason I'm here in the first place is because of you.
我爱你  也欠你的
I love you and I owe you.
但这已经不是你一个人的公司了
But it's not just your company. Not anymore.
你有种很特别的才华  孩子
You got-- you got a special kind of talent, sweetheart.
但如果你按自己的节拍走
But when you march to the beat of your own drum,
就可能失去整个乐队
you risk losin' the band.
说出你的想法
Lay out your vision.
想办法跟她合作
Find a way to work with her.
你俩需要彼此
You two need each other.
博斯
Hey, Bos?
我结婚了
I got married.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
你知道在给你开派对吧  不能回头说吗
You do realize you have a party going on? This can't wait?
不能  请坐下
No. Please sit down.
我对穆特尼的走向
I've had some concerns
有些担忧
about Mutiny's direction,
而我没能好好表达这些担忧
concerns I haven't effectively expressed.
这怪我
That's on me.
现在我们发展得很快
Things are moving fast,
比我预期的快得多
faster than I ever imagined they would.
这很令人激动
It's an exciting time.
但我们走到了十字路口
But we are at a crossroads
我们需要做决定  一起决定
and we have a decision to make... together.
我知道你们都想上市
I know you all want to move forward on the IPO.
我也想
I do, too.
但我认为急着上市  对我们并不是最好的
But I don't think rushing into it is in our best interests.
我能说一句吗
Can I say a quick word?
公司的价值在于它现在的状况
The company is valued for what it is and does right now.
市场现在喜欢穆特尼  但再过一两年
The market likes Mutiny, but in a year or two,
或者等我们实施完毕
or however long it takes to implement
你所构想的改变  谁知道呢
the changes you have in mind, who knows?
我们不能指望未来的情势还跟如今一样
We can't count on tomorrow's landscape looking like today's.
穆特尼现在的样子是维持不下去的
Mutiny isn't sustainable as it exists now.
我们整个用户群都是康懋达64用户
Our whole user base is tied to the Commodore 64.
我们想要发展就得开发其他平台
We need to diversify to other platforms in order to grow.
这不就是华尔街喜欢的吗  发展
And isn't that what Wall Street likes? Growth?
我所构想的投资
The kind of investment that I'm talking about
日后终会有收获
in time and money will pay off
聪明的投资者会明白的
and smart investors will see that.
你的点子很棒  卡梅伦
Your ideas are good, Cameron,
有些非常好
and some of them are even great.
我也想跟你一起探索你的每个点子
And I want to explore them with you, all of them.
但为什么不能在
But why can't we do that
上市之后做呢
after we've gone public?
我们不用等着把它做到完美
We don't have to wait to try and make something perfect.
完美是好的敌人
Perfect is the enemy of good,
穆特尼现在就很好了
and Mutiny is very, very good right now as it is.
唐娜  你最近上过跳蚤市场吗
Donna, have you been on SwapMeet lately?
就像个8位的商场
It's like an 8-bit mall.
它失去了其社区的本质
It's lost what made it a community.
我们得重新给它注入活力
We need to make it feel alive again
否则大家会离开的
or people are going to leave
只剩下我们给一群三流小店开商场
and we'll just be hosting a bunch of tacky businesses
叫卖破烂  没人买
selling junk to nobody.
但是
But--
求你
Please.
我们不能太天真
We can't afford to be naive here.
如果我们推迟改变
If we put off these changes,
就不能好好施行它们了
we won't be able to make them the right way.
是按你的方式吧
You mean your way.
我们将会太过在意市盈率
I mean, we'll be so focused on PE ratios
和股东价值
and shareholder value,
而不能迅速创新  反应
that we won't be able to innovate and respond quickly.
穆特尼就不再是穆特尼了
Mutiny won't be Mutiny anymore.
我们会失去公司的灵魂
We'll lose the company's soul.
如果按你的办法来
Say we do it your way.
万一你的点子  虽然它们很棒
What happens if your ideas, good as they are,
但行不通或适得其反了呢
don't work or backfire?
那我们就可能丧失现在的价值
We risk losing our current valuation.
上市不代表就要停止创新
Going public doesn't mean we stop innovating.
我们可以同时继续实验  改进
We can continue to experiment and improve as we go,
尤其有你这样聪明的人给我们带路
especially with someone as brilliant as you leading the way.
别哄我
Don't patronize me.
我没那个意思
I'm not patronizing you.
你又像以往一样在对付我  我受够了
You're handling me like you always do, and I'm sick of it.
我在向公司股东解释
Listen, I'm trying to explain some very real risks
真实存在
that you're not willing to acknowledge
而你不肯承认的风险
to actual stakeholders in the company.
我们不能太冲动
We can't afford to be impulsive here.
你还说我冲动
You're calling me impulsive?
这话什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
我觉得外面的人就在庆祝你的冲动
I think people are out there celebrating what that means.
你是指你为了不让我发现
Oh, you mean that bullshit little party you threw
你背后捅刀行为而开的破派对吗
to distract me from getting stabbed in the back?
-好啊  -行了  女士们
- Okay. - Okay, ladies,
我们偏离主题了
we are getting off track here.
黛安  她说的大多是你的想法
Diane, it's mostly your thoughts coming out of her mouth,
所以我不知你还能提出什么新意见
so I can't imagine what you have to add to the discussion.
天呐  真不知我们谁该更觉得受冒犯
Jesus! I don't know who should be more insulted.
相信我  如果我说什么
Trust me, if I'm expressing an opinion,
那肯定是我的想法
it's because I believe it.
我是该相信你
I should trust you. Yes, of course!
除非你又在撒谎
I mean, unless you're lying now,
就像之前你在道格和克雷格的事上撒了谎
like you lied about Doug and Craig.
你知道吗
Did you know about that?
你告诉她可以解雇他们
That when you told her it was fine if I fired them,
结果她却告诉我必须留下他们
she told me that I had to keep them on?
你就想跟这种人
Is that the sort of person
继续做生意吗
that you wanna trust with this business going forward?
你是指一个
You mean the kind of person
努力想维持下去
who actually tries to make things work
而不是跟每个
instead of fighting with
威胁了她"救世主情节"的人打架的人吗
anybody who threatens her "savior complex"?
我跟人相处得很好
I get along fine with people.
你疏远每一个人
You alienate everybody.
你一个想尽一切理由不回家
Says the woman that will take any excuse
见她丈夫的女人也好意思说
not to go home to her husband.
先看看你的婚姻能不能坚持到明年
Why don't we see if your marriage lasts the year
你再提出感情建议吧
before you start dolg out relationship advice?
-唐娜  -够了
- Donna? - Enough. Enough!
这次会议结束了
Hey, this meeting is over, all right?
天呐  你俩去各自的角落
My God! You two go to your corners,
把嘴上的血都擦干净
wipe the blood off your mouths,
我们稍后再...
and we will revisit-- -
这事今晚就定下来
This gets decided tonight.
我要大家投票  清楚明白
I want a vote, and I want it clean.
如果你们都同意唐娜
If you all decide with Donna,
那就自己去上市吧
then you can go ahead and do the IPO without me.
-我辞职  -卡梅伦  别这样
- I quit. - Cameron, come on.
不  我受够了
No! I'm sick of this!
去吧  好好看看这家公司
Go! Take a hard look at this company
问问自己  是谁塑造了它
and ask yourself who made it what it is
又是谁只是搭了顺风车
and who's just been along for the ride!
卡梅伦  别这样
Cameron, please don't do this.
你想投票  好啊
You want it? You got it.
但我不会坐视这家公司
But I will not sit by and watch this company die
因为被个任性的孩子挟持而死去
because it's being held hostage by a petulant child.
如果我们不上市
If we don't move forward with the IPO,
你就自己驾船去撞礁石吧
then you can steer this ship into the rocks yourself,
我不干了
because I am outta here.
博斯说得对  我们休息下  冷静下来
Okay, Bos is right. Let's take a beat, cool off--
举手表决  谁赞成现在上市
Show of hands. Who's in favor of doing the IPO now
不管一切后果
with all that that entails?
你真让我心碎
You're breaking my goddamn heart.
乔
Joe?
你来做什么
What are you doin' here?
总得有人来送钥匙
Someone had to drop off the keys.
欢迎来到你的帝国
Welcome to your empire.
参观结束
And thus concludes the grand tour.
好了  注意
All right, pay attention.
这很复杂
This is-- this is complicated.
这个  是大楼钥匙
Okay, this one-- this key's for the building.
这个是女厕  这个是男厕
This key is for the ladies' room, for the men's bathroom,
这俩是前门的
and those two are for the front door.
谢谢
Thanks.
如果不能是我
If it wasn't gonna be me,
我很高兴会是你
I'm glad it was you.
记得从未来写信给我
Write me from the future.
-49%  -什么
- 49 percent. - What?
来跟我一起经营
Come run it with me...
我就给你49%的股份
and 49 percent of the company's yours.
这玩笑好残忍
That's a cruel joke,
也不像你的作风
and quite frankly, beneath you.
我是认真的
I'm serious.
49%
49 percent.
考虑到别人会怎么想  我们得放聪明点
With how this looks, we need to be smart.
我该做匿名合伙人
I should be a silent partner.
那更好
Even better.
乔
Joe.
莱恩  今天对我们很重要
Ryan, today is a big day for us.
你已经见到了
So, you've seen it already?
见到什么
Seen what?
那你还不知道
So, then you don't know.
我将麦克米伦实用网络的
I released the source code for MacMillan Utility's
杀毒软件源代码公诸于众了
security software to the public.
-你说什么呢  -免费了  乔
- What are you talking about? - It's free, Joe.
真真正正的免费了  就像我们想的那样
Really free, like we always wanted.
大家可以修补它  改进它
People can tinker with it, they can make it better--
也可能会把它搞坏
or worse, that can happen, too.
但是麦克米伦实用网络
The point is MacMillan Utility
再不能靠它盈利了
can no longer profit off of it.
但这是违法的
But that's illegal.
我还向媒体泄露了
And I released documents to the media
能证明麦克米伦实用网络
proving that MacMillan Utility
本就支持2.0版收费的文件
was totally on board with charging the public for 2.0 all along,
你受攻击是因为你想阻止他们
and they only went after you when you tried to stop them.
这能表明他们并不是想保护大家
Yeah, it shows that they weren't trying the protect people
或是保证大家的安全
or-- or keep them safe.
他们只是想利用他们
They were just going to exploit them.
我还向媒体说明
And I laid out for the media
你是如何为守护理想而丢了工作
how you lost your job defending your ideals.
你知道你做了什么吗
Do you have any idea what you've done?
是的  我如你所愿  还击了他们
Yes! I returned volley just like you wanted.
他们要好几年才能缓过来
It's gonna take those bastards years to recover.
他们不会放过你的
They are gonna come after you.
我不傻  乔
I'm not stupid, Joe.
我完全掩盖了自己的踪迹
I covered every conceivable track.
他们肯定抓不到我  我就那么厉害
They will never catch me. I am that good.
没人那么厉害
Yeah, nobody's that good.
我就有
I am.
走着瞧吧
Yeah, we'll see.